Miyazaki stands radiantly
in the beauty of the desert.
But what's that?
An odd figure appears from beyond the dunes.
Some weirdo is coming this way.
Isn't that person coming
straight toward Miyazaki?
A ransom kidnapper? Perhaps, a
robber? An anti-government guerrilla?
Hold on. He looks Japanese.
Anno?
What in the world.
Yes, it's the director of Evangelion, Anno.
Two popular movies were released last summer alongside Princess Mononoke.
On top of working with Miyazaki on
Nausicaa of the Valley of the Wind,
the two have a good mentor/pupil relationship.
Alright, who did this?
What is Anno doing in the Sahara desert?
The answer is the producer
Suzuki wanted to scare Miyazaki.
However, he won't get mad just from being tricked.
This kind of fooling around
might spur Ghibli's imagination.
With that...
Are we good to go?
If we talk here we'll only
scratch surface level topics.
Towering east of the Sahara
Desert are the Atlas Mountains.
In the city's luxury hotel grows a lush background of
greenery unimaginable
against its desert surroundings.
Here, the world's most
prided directors sit down to talk.
First, a word about each other's works.
I feel that your greatest
strength is being honest.
Like how you created Evangelion, an honest work.
You created something that didn't deviate from your personality.
What are your thoughts on Princess Mononoke?
I can't say that when he's right here.
Exactly. I'm not going to fix it.
When I'm working....I don't know what it
is, but I feel like all my troubles disappear.
I want to work.
I think I have the most fun
animating when I've hit my limit.
Hitting your limit is no fun at all.
I enjoy it.
I feel alive when it's
down to the last stretch,
and there's uncertainty whether
it'll be finished in time or not.
I'm perfectly fine without that.
After some sparse chitchat Miyazaki said this:
It's all luck. If you make it, they will come.
You can draw in the children and make them smile.
Whether they genuinely enjoy it is the real battle.
Don't underestimate this old man.
That'll bite them in the butt.
When I think about how I haven't
reached some people, I feel empty.
I have to start from square one and study,
ah but I don't want to. I just have to try.
Study and work towards putting a smile
on the faces of children everywhere.
Don't these sound like words from a
man that might retract his retirement?
After 3 years, Miyazaki completed
production on Princess Mononoke.
This trip to the Sahara with the staff and friends
was a way to rejuvenate after such a long process.
And inside the mind of the refreshed Miyazaki...